The school's official website is
学校官网上
[Pay attention to mental growth]
全是他们的通报批评
Their grades are basically at the bottom of the class as well.
成绩也基本都是班级吊车尾
No honors,
没有荣誉
and no shot at competitions.
与竞赛无缘
It seems that this time,
看来这次
it's really just going to be a one-round tour for show.
真的就只是走走过场的一轮游
Let me just meet them openly.
大大方方见个面吧
Hello, teacher.
老师好
[Fu Xinshu, former captain of the football team]
您是新来的领队老师吗
Yes, my surname is Lin.
是的 我姓林
Hello, Ms. Lin.
小林老师好
My name is Fu Xinshu.
我叫付新书
"Ms. Lin"?
小林老师
I've already told them to hurry up.
他们我已经催过了
They should be here soon.
应该马上就会到
I bought you guys some milk tea.
给你们买了奶茶
You can distribute it later.
待会你分一下
Okay, thank you, Ms. Lin.
好 谢谢老师
Fu Xinshu.
付新书
Were you also on the football team before?
你以前也是足球队的吗
Yes.
对
What position?
什么位置
I used to play midfield.
以前是踢中场的
"Used to"?
以前
What about now?
那现在呢
I haven't played football for a long time now.
现在已经好久不踢球了
Wen Chengye!
文成业同学
So he's Wen Chengye.
他就是文成业
You know me?
你认识我
You're the transfer student from Class 4.
你是四班的转学生
You and your skateboard are both very famous.
你跟你的滑板都很有名
Ms. Lin, I'll go rush them again.
老师我再去催催他们
Hurry up. Come on.
快点 快点
Wen Chengye?
文成业
What? Are you here for the meeting, too?
怎么你也是来开会的
Wen Chengye.
文成业同学
Please stay for the meeting.
开完会再走吧
-Who does he think he is? -Who cares about him?
拽什么呢 谁稀罕啊
-Just ignore him, Boss. -Yeah.
别理他老大 就是
Teacher?
老师
It's you!
是你
There's milk tea!
居然有奶茶
-Teacher, -How come it's her?
老师 怎么是她啊
you bought the milk tea, didn't you?
奶茶是你买的吧
Come and enjoy it.
快来喝吧
Okay!
好嘞
Boss, here you are.
老大 给你
The teacher even bought us milk tea.
老师还给买了奶茶
She bought us milk tea.
买了奶茶
The new teacher is so beautiful and kind.
新老师真是人美心善啊
-Fu! -There's milk tea for us!
老付 居然有奶茶喝
How come you guys arrived even later than us?
你们几个怎么来得比我们还晚
-So what? -So what, bro?
那咋了 那咋了兄弟
Feng Suo, the teacher said
冯锁 老师说了
there's no milk tea for those who are late.
迟到的不能喝奶茶
-We will... We will drink it anyway. -Bro.
我们就我们就喝 兄弟
Master Zhi Hui was the last one to get here,
来得最晚的是智会大师
not me, right?
可不是我吧
Master,
大师
which direction is lucky today?
今日哪个方位大吉啊
Anyway,
反正
it's not your position, Zheng Ren.
不是郑仁你这个位置
Mr. Zhi Hui,
智会老师
how about here? How about my position?
我这我这怎么样
Not good, either.
也不咋地
Yours is surely not...
你绝对不是
It's definitely not your position.
绝对不在你这
It must be me,
肯定是我
the chosen one.
天选之人
I'm sure it's not you.
包管不是你
There he goes again, the Master.
大师又来了
A one-round tour is guaranteed.
一轮游稳了
All right, enough.
好了好了
Here's our team supervisor.
我们的领队老师
Ms. Lin, everyone is here...
老师 我们都到齐了
except for Wen Chengye.
除了文成业
Here, I'm announcing something.
我宣布一件事
The school is arranging for you guys to participate in a football match.
学校准备组织大家参加足球赛
I will serve as your temporary team supervisor.
暂时由我带队
My surname is Lin.
我姓林
Football match?
足球赛
At 2:30 PM this Sunday,
周日下午两点半
let's meet at the school gate to play...
校门口集合 去参加
in the Youth Super League qualifiers.
青超联赛预选赛
Our rival is Ning'an Experimental School.
对手是宁安实验
Ning'an Experimental School's team is super strong.
宁安实验超强啊
We definitely can't beat them.
我们肯定踢不过
How about we forfeit again?
不如我们继续弃赛吧
Yeah, let's forfeit.
对啊 弃赛吧
We haven't trained for 2 years.
两年不训练了
What are we going for?
去干嘛
Exactly.
是啊
To make a fool of ourselves?
出洋相吗
Our football team has been disbanded for so long.
我们球队解散这么长时间了
Why are we still playing?
还有球要踢啊
Yeah, why?
就是
-Play for what? -I'm not going anyway.
踢什么踢啊 反正我不去
They all seem very negative.
看起来态度都很消极
Those who don't show up will fail PE,
不到场的同学体育成绩不及格
and we'll notify your parents.
通知家长
I'll take down the names.
我记下名字
Ms. Lin, you probably don't have that right, I think?
老师 您应该没这个权限吧
Director Qian gave me this right.
钱主任给了我这个权限
Fu Xinshu,
付新书
have everyone sign this later.
待会你让大家签字
Fu, we've already shown you respect.
老付 面子是给到你了
-Goodbye. -Bye-bye.
再见 拜拜
Bye-bye.
拜拜
Ms. Lin,
老师
they don't care about failing,
不及格这种事他们是不会在乎的
because they fail almost every subject.
因为他们几乎每科都不及格
But I'll try my best to get them all there.
但我会努力让他们都到的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Boss, are we really not playing that match?
老大那比赛咱们真不踢啊
The team was easily disbanded back then.
当初球队说解散就解散
Now they want me back?
现在想让我回去
What do they take me for?
我是什么
That's true, but...
确实是这么一说吧 但是
Did you buy this for me?
你给我买的
It definitely wasn't from me.
肯定不是我送的呀
Could it...
这
be from Xiaotian?
不能是小甜给我买的吧
The Class Beauty wouldn't have such bad taste, would she?
班花同学应该没这么不开眼吧
Bao Xiaotian has good taste,
包小甜就是有眼光
having taken a liking to you, Boss.
能看得上我们老大
Lin Lu, did you just call me?
林鹿同学你叫我
Bao Xiaotian,
包小甜
what do you think of my boss?
你觉得我老大怎么样
I don't know him at all.
我 完全不熟
There's a second way to solve this question.
这道题还有第二种解法
Can you stop being so nosy?
就你多嘴是吧
Don't you know girls are easily embarrassed?
你不知道女孩的脸皮很薄啊
My bad, my bad.
都怪我都怪我
Open it and see.
拆开看看
What do you think
你说
she got me as a gift?
她能送我啥礼物
Are you sure it's from her?
你确定是她送的
Why wouldn't it be?
怎么不是她送的
-Do you have a death wish? -Okay, fine.
活得不耐烦了吧你 好好好
Chocolate?
巧克力 纸条
Ms. Lin,
老师
what does this mean?
这什么意思啊
It was definitely you who did this, right?
肯定是你干的对吧
Do you feel uncertain about your life?
你对自己的人生充满困惑吗
Do you still not know where your future is heading?
你仍不知道未来要走向何方吗
Lin of No. 8 High School specializes in treating
八中小林专治厌学逃学
school refusal, truancy, lack of motivation, and poor grades.
不愿学不出成绩等疑难杂症
Did you do this, too?
这也是你干的
You really love playing pranks, Ms. Lin.
老师真爱恶作剧啊
Childish.
幼稚
Not only did you give me a little gift,
你不仅给我送小礼物
but you also gave one to Chen Jianghe?
你还给陈江河送
And you, bro.
还有你兄弟
You actually believed it? You're so naive.
真信啊 天真啊
I started working here
我是这周一
this Monday, September 2nd, for the first day.
九月二号来学校入的第一天职
You registered last week,
报到的时候是上周
before I even got here.
我还没来
Furthermore,
再者
where did you find it?
你是在哪发现的
In my desk drawer.
桌肚里啊
Then tell me, my dear student, Qin Ao.
那请问亲爱的秦敖同学
In broad daylight,
光天化日之下
how did I go hide this chocolate
我是怎么去你桌肚里
in your desk drawer without being seen?
塞这个巧克力不被发现
It was computer class this morning.
上午是电脑课啊
So you could sneak into the classroom.
老师可以溜进溜进教室啊
Besides, you just look like a student.
而且老师长得本身就像学生
Thank you.
我谢谢你啊
But I'm not into that.
我没这个癖好
I
我本人
graduated with a master's degree from Yongchuan University.
永川大学硕士研究生毕业
I was our province's top liberal arts scorer in the college entrance exam.
省高考文科状元
I have published 6 SCI papers in total—
共发表六篇SCI论文
4 as the first author.
其中四篇一作
I've received first-class scholarships for 7 years.
七年一等奖学金获得者
If I hadn't wanted to live a life of just getting by,
如果不是我想过混吃等死的日子
why would I have ended up sitting here?
为什么要坐在这儿
Ms. Lin,
老师
isn't it inappropriate for you to brag so much?
你这么自吹自擂是不是不太好
Ms. Lin, was it really not you?
老师 真不是你
Then why is your phone number on it?
那为什么上面是你的电话
It also asks us to come to you.
还写着让我们来找你
It must have something to do with you.
肯定和你有关
Think it over again, Ms. Lin.
老师你再想想
Boss, let's go over there to check it out.
老大我们去那边看看
There's a note in every piece of chocolate.
每个巧克力里面都有小纸条
What are these? I don't understand.
这都啥啊 看不懂
Nine of them have words on them.
九张有字
Why doesn't this one have any?
为啥这张没有
How should I know?
我怎么知道
Ms. Lin,
老师
aren't you a master's graduate
你不是永川大学的
from Yongchuan University,
硕士研究生毕业
the province's top liberal arts scorer in the college entrance exam,
还是什么省高考文科状元
and a straight-A student who wrote
共写了多少篇那个
some SOS papers?
什么SOS论文的大学霸
You should know, right?
不应该吧
It's "SCI."
那是SCI
I know.
我知道
The straight-A student can't even solve this?
不会大学霸也解不出来吧
If I can't solve a puzzle,
我解不开这个问题
there could only be two possibilities.
那只有两种可能性
Firstly, it's not a puzzle at all.
第一 这根本不是个谜题
Secondly, I don't want to solve it for now.
第二 我暂时没想解开它
Each sentence has a different length.
每句话长短不一
There is a repeated word.
有一个重复的字
Is it a crossword puzzle?
难道是填字游戏
Okay.
好啊
The grid for puzzle solving.
解谜用的方盘格
Got it.
有了
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
have you found anything?
你是有什么发现吗
"Xin-shu."
新 书
Which word do you think
你们觉得
should be filled in the front?
前面应该填哪个字
Isn't that self-evident?
这不是废话吗
It must be...
肯定是
-"Fu."
付
What brings you here?
你们怎么来了
Hello, Ms. Lin.
林老师好
What's up?
什么事儿
Did you guys change your mind
你们不会想通了
and decide to play in the match this weekend?
周末要来比赛吧
No way!
怎么可能
Bro, it's daytime.
大哥现在是白天
Wake up, please.
你醒醒吧
I don't play meaningless matches.
我不踢无意义的比赛
We can't win anyway.
我们又赢不了
I know.
我知道
But what if I
但如果我还是想
still want to invite you to play?
请你们参加比赛呢
Let's get down to business.
我们说正事吧
Someone played a prank on me.
有人恶作剧我
Simply put,
就简单说
someone gave us a puzzle,
有一个人给我们出了一个谜题
a crossword puzzle.
叫填字游戏
And this is our deduction process.
然后就是这是我们推测的过程
We've deduced that your name goes in this blank.
我们推测这个空是填你的名字
-"Xinshu." -You are the one related
新书 你是和我们
to Ms. Lin and us.
还有小林老师都有关系的人
So the answer must be you.
答案肯定是你
Why me?
为什么是我
Even though he's
虽然他是
-the one who wants to play the most... -We also inferred it from this hint...
全队最想参加比赛的那一个
Did you receive anything similar?
就是你有没有收到类似
Judging from his reaction,
但就他目前的反应来看
he didn't do this.
这事不是他干的
My brain hurts.
烧脑
Let's go. Time to go home for dinner.
走了 回家吃饭
I remember now.
我想起来了
I did receive something.
我有收到过
Really?
真的
What is it?
什么东西
I'll tell you if you come to play
如果你们能来参加周末的比赛
in the match this weekend.
我就告诉你们
Hold on.
等等
You're still one player short
要组建球队
for the team, right?
还差一名球员吧
I'll handle it.
我会搞定的
I don't know how to do the homework the teacher assigned last time.
上次老师留的那个作业不会做
Same here. I've been looking it up for a long time.
我也不会 查了好久呢
Wen Chengye...
文成业
What do you want from me?
找我干嘛
Just say it.
有事说事
You left early today,
今天你早退了
so you didn't hear it.
没听到
This Sunday afternoon at 2:30,
周日下午两点半
we'll meet at the school gate for the match.
校门口集合去比赛
Can you join us?
你能参加吗
You've waited for so long.
等了这么久
Is this very important to you?
这事对你很重要吗
Very important.
非常重要
Ever since the team disbanded,
球队解散到现在
what I want to do most is
我最想干的事情
to play football with everyone once again.
就是和伙伴们再一起踢球
I also hope you can join us as our new teammate.
也希望你能成为我们的新伙伴
Okay.
好
I will definitely go
我一定去
and arrive on time.
准时到
The lights are off?
没亮灯
So he is home.
原来他在家
No way,
不是吧
is he bathing in the dark?
关灯泡澡
Or did he forget to turn off the water?
还是忘关水了
This guy is too weird.
这人也太奇怪了
Hello,
喂 您好
I'd like to know
我想了解一下
about the new tenant upstairs.
楼上那位新租客的情况
I know he pays a lot of rent,
我知道他租金给得多
but I still need to know
但他的基本信息
his basic information, right?
我总要了解一下吧
If he's really that rich,
他要是真有钱的话
why didn't he rent a luxury apartment?
他怎么不去租高级公寓啊
Just because he's handsome doesn't mean he's a good person.
长得帅就一定是好人了
Come on, sir.
不是中介先生
Just think it over. I'm not joking with you.
你想想我没在跟你开玩笑
Installing a bathtub in the living room
在这种老式居民楼的
of this old residential building
客厅里安装浴缸
and bathing in the dark—
黑灯瞎火地泡澡
don't you think it's so weird?
你不觉得很奇怪吗
What if he's some psycho killer?
万一他是那种变态杀人狂怎么办
Think about how dangerous it is for me to live here alone.
你想想我一个人住在这里多危险
Okay.
好
Please make sure you investigate this thoroughly for me.
麻烦你一定要帮我调查清楚
You're still up now?
还没睡觉啊
It's only 9 o'clock.
现在才九点
Um,
那个
since when have you been standing here?
你是什么时候站在这的
Not long ago.
不久
Just since you started making that call.
就从你打电话开始
That's great.
挺好的
I'm used to sleeping early and waking up early.
我习惯早睡早起
Then I'll get in now.
那我先进去了
I am 30 years old,
我 三十岁
from Yongchuan, unemployed.
籍贯永川 无业
Good night,
晚安
Miss Landlady.
房东小姐
I don't want to kill you yet.
我现在还不想杀你
I've only been at work for 2 days,
这才上班两天
and I've already received 2 little gifts.
就收到两份小礼物
A football lending card.
借球卡
A little note.
小纸条
I was also asked to rebuild the football team as the supervisor.
还被要求重组球队做领队
Who on earth is messing with me,
到底是谁在捉弄我呀
and why?
目的是什么
And the QR Code upstairs
还有楼上的二维码
is also weird.
奇奇怪怪的
Is there any connection
他们之间
between them?
有关联吗
Do you have any idea?
你知道吗
Out for a morning workout?
去晨练
You got the pancakes from this restaurant?
你买到这家饼了
The line is usually super long.
要排队很久的
They are freshly baked.
刚出炉的
Try some?
尝尝
No, thanks. I have a match to go to.
不用了 我要去比赛
We still don't have everyone here yet.
到现在人都不齐
Come on...
不是这
Even though I don't want to play, I still arrived early.
我不想踢我都早来
In view of this pre-match gathering alone,
光看赛前集合这情况
you can already tell today's match is
就知道今天这比赛
looking rough.
悬了
Are you giving up already?
你们这就认输啦
What? We're obviously going to lose.
怎么着 不用想也知道会输
Watch your mouth.
瞧你那张破嘴
I'm in the team.
有我在
I once dribbled past 5 players in a row and scored with one kick.
当年我可是连过五人一脚定
And now?
那现在呢
You pant after running 2 laps.
跑两圈就喘
A true hero doesn't boast of past glory.
好汉不提当年勇
-I mean, I can still do it now, okay? -Keep bragging.
我说我现在也行好吧
Ms. Lin, is there no milk tea today?
老师 今天没有奶茶吗
Is everyone here?
人都到齐了吗
Where's Wen Chengye?
文成业呢
Fu!
老付
Are you sure Wen Chengye promised to come today?
你确定文成业答应你今天他会来
Is he too scared of losing to show up?
不会是怕输不敢来了吧
"I'm not coming, you idiot"?
我不来了蠢货 你
It's fine, Fu.
没事老付
I... I'll get revenge for you later.
我 我到时候给你报仇
Great.
这下可好了
Ms. Lin, since Wen Chengye isn't coming,
老师 这下文成业不来
we don't even have enough players.
我们人都凑不齐
Let's just disband right here.
我们直接原地解散吧
You've got a point. I'll go tell Director Qian.
有道理 我去告诉钱主任
It's time! Why haven't you gotten on the bus?
它到点了怎么还不上车
The match is about to start!
要比赛了呀
Director Qian, here's the thing.
钱主任是这样的
Wen Chengye got held up and couldn't make it.
文成业突然有事不来了
The team is one player short.
球队少了一个人
Can we just not go?
你看是不是可以不去了
If he's not coming, we'll find someone else!
他不来我们找别人呐
What do you mean by "not go"?
不去是什么意思
The school leaders are taking this very seriously today.
今天学校领导对这个很重视
How can you just forfeit easily?
怎么能说弃赛就弃赛呢
But we don't have enough players.
但人不够啊
Then let's figure it out!
人不够我们想办法呀
Don't pull a long face.
别拉着脸
It's my treat today!
今天钱主任请客
Come on, have some goodies.
来来来 吃好吃的
Don't pull a long face. Give me a smile.
别拉着那个脸 笑一笑
I bought some snacks for you.
给你们买的小零食
You're usually so cute.
平时很可爱的
Don't look so down.
别拉着个脸
You usually have the brightest smile.
你平时的笑最灿烂
Come on, here you are.
来 来 来
-Thank you, Director.
谢谢主任 谢谢主任
Thank you, Director.
谢谢主任
Here's for you.
这给你
Don't worry, just go ahead.
放心尽管去
Leave this matter to me.
这个事交给我了
I promise before you even arrive,
我保证没等你们先到
the substitute will already be waiting there for you.
那个替补已经在现场等你们了
Take it.
拿着
Get in the bus!
上车 谢谢
Hurry up! Stop dawdling!
快 还墨迹
Stop messing around. Hurry!
还皮 快点
It's getting late!
时间不早了
Go! Get moving! Get on the bus!
快 快 快 上车
Get on! Get on now!
上车 上车 上车
This bus is pretty fancy.
这车也太豪华了吧
And they're well-equipped.
这装备整挺全啊
I'm so jealous.
好羡慕啊
-Thank you, Coach.
谢谢教练 谢谢教练
-Hurry up! -Come on!
速度 速度
Their conditions are way too good.
这条件也太好了
That's a bit too much.
夸张
They're so delicate.
娇气
Hurry up.
快快快
Let me take this.
我拿这个
Boss, I want this treatment, too.
老大我也想要这种待遇
Then you should ask Ms. Lin for it.
那你得问小林老师
What supplies do we have?
我们有什么补给啊
I ordered some water for you
我在附近的农家乐
from a nearby farmhouse.
给你们外卖点了些水
Oh, God...
服了 走吧 走吧 走吧
Here we are.
到了啊
Come on, get off.
来来来下车
Relax and play well.
都放松心态好好比赛啊
-Okay! -Okay.
好
When did we get another football team?
咱什么时候多了个足球队啊
They came for the chemistry competition,
人家是化学竞赛的
taking the test in the building over there.
来隔壁楼考竞赛
Chemistry has always been
化学一直是宏景
Hongjing's strongest subject in competitions.
最强势的竞赛科目
I'm coming!
我来了 我来了
Chen Weidong from the track and field team?
田径队 陈卫东
I came right after Director Qian
钱主任刚和我说完
talked to me.
我就过来了
So everyone's here. Let's go.
人都到齐了 走吧
-Let's go.
走 走
Stop there.
别动
Everyone, show your faces.
所有人脸露出来
Why bother taking photos if it's going to be a one-round tour?
随便踢踢的一轮游有什么好拍的
She was probably just completing a photo task
估计在完成钱主任交代的
assigned by Director Qian.
拍照任务
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
can I really do it?
我真的可以吗
Chen Weidong,
陈卫东
we never thought about winning.
我们都没想着赢
Why are you taking it so seriously?
你那么认真干嘛
Bro, Wen Chengye didn't come,
兄弟那个姓文的不来
but you did.
你能来
You have my respect.
敬你三分
Ning'an united,
宁安一心
fighting only for the championship!
只争冠军
Should we also come up with a slogan together?
我们是不是也得一起想个口号
What's there to think about?
这想啥呀
We're just here to run a few laps,
我们来这就是随便跑两圈
lose the game, and put on a show.
输个球演个戏嘛
Then we have to put on a full show.
那演戏也得演全套啊
Come on.
来
Who can come up with a slogan?
谁来想个口号
Qi Liang, let Qi Liang do it.
祁亮 那祁亮想吧
Why don't you do it?
你怎么不想
Aren't you always talkative?
你话不是多吗
Then I'll come up with one.
那我想了啊
Hongjing, Hongjing, shining stars!
宏景宏景闪亮新星
-That's so tacky. -Oh...
好土啊 这
Then you think of one.
那你来
Gather here.
快过来
If you don't join me, I'll tell Director Qian about it.
不参与的我告诉钱主任了
There you go again,
又是钱主任
bringing up Director Qian.
又钱主任
Come on.
来吧来吧
Director Qian.
钱主任
Hongjing, Hongjing, shining stars!
宏景宏景闪亮新星
-Hongjing, Hongjing...
宏景宏景
Say it louder.
喊呀
-shining stars!
闪亮新星
Let's go.
走走走走
Today's match is about to start.
今天的比赛即将开始
The two teams are
两支队伍分别是
Ning'an Experimental School and Hongjing No. 8 High School.
宁安实验和宏景八中
The match officially begins.
比赛正式开始
First up, there's a coin toss to choose sides.
赛前先进行掷硬币选边
The ones in blue and black striped uniforms are from Ning'an Experimental School.
身穿蓝黑条纹队服的是宁安实验
Their team is extremely fast
他们的球队速度非常快
and known as the "Cheetahs."
享有猎豹之名
The team in the blue jerseys is Hongjing No. 8 High School.
而身穿蓝色球衣的是宏景八中
They haven't participated in any match for 2 years.
他们已经两年没有参加过比赛了
In fact, just 2 months without playing
实际上两个月不踢
can completely change a team.
就已经判若两队
And they've been absent for 2 whole years.
而他们整整缺席了两年
In the football fans' eyes,
在球迷看来
their chances of winning look slim.
他们的赢面不大
The 2 forwards of Hongjing No. 8 High School
宏景八中的两位前锋
are No. 9, Qin Ao,
分别是九号秦敖
and No. 7, Chen Jianghe.
和七号陈江河
Chen Jianghe is
陈江河呢
good at one-touch finishing in the box.
擅长一脚触球完成抢点
As for Qin Ao,
秦敖呢
he's good at using changes of pace
擅长利用节奏变化
to pull off one-on-one dribbles.
完成一对一突破
This is Hongjing No. 8 High School's goalkeeper,
这是宏景八中的门将
No. 1, Feng Suo.
一号冯锁
He is the team's last line of defense.
他是球队的最后一道防线
Hongjing's 2 core defenders
宏景的两名核心后卫
are No. 6, Lin Lu, and No. 5, Yu Ming.
分别是六号林鹿和五号俞明
Because of his small stature, Lin Lu was
林鹿因为个子小
once jokingly called
曾被戏称为
a player who'd jump up and shatter your knees.
跳起来踢碎你膝盖的选手
Next to him is Yu Ming,
他旁边的俞明
capable of charging down the flanks.
有着一定的边路冲锋能力
The 2 teams are making their final pre-match preparations.
两队在进行最后的赛前准备
I wonder if it's because the ones
宏景八中
from Hongjing No. 8 High School
不知道是不是因为
haven't played for so long,
太久没踢比赛
but they look a bit loose.
看上去啊有些松散
QR Code?
二维码
What is he doing here?
他怎么在这
Come on! Go for it!
加油加油
Mark your men
盯好自己的人
and watch the timing!
看好时机
Come on!
加油
The match begins!
比赛开始
Ning'an Experimental School's team kicks off.
由宁安实验队开球
Their passing speed is very fast.
他们传球的速度很快
Hongjing No. 8 High School stands no chance
宏景八中根本没有机会
to intercept the ball.
抢断足球
The situation is instantly under Ning'an Team's control.
局势瞬间被宁安队掌控
-Hongjing No. 8 High School's captain, -Mark him!
宏景八中的队长十号付新书
No. 10 Fu Xinshu, is like Hongjing's midfield engine.
他是宏景的中场引擎
He commands the team's defense
由他指挥全队防守
and is the heart of the entire Hongjing Team.
是宏景整个队伍的大心脏
I didn't expect to be this fun participating
没想到参加这样的高中联赛
in such a high school league.
还是挺开心的
These kids aren't entirely useless.
这些孩子也不是那么废柴嘛
It's so passionate!
太热血了吧
This is their true battlefield.
这才是他们的战场
I suddenly feel that
忽然觉得
football is actually quite fun.
足球也挺好玩的
Shoot!
打门
So fast? Has it even been a minute?
这么快 有到一分钟吗
They can't be this bad, right?
不会这么菜吧
Goal! One to zero.
球进了 一比零
Ning'an Experimental School scored the first goal.
宁安实验先下一城
The Hongjing No. 8 High School's players
宏景八中的球员的状态
look nowhere near as good as before.
似乎远不如前啊
During the 2 years they haven't competed,
没参加比赛这两年
did they do nothing but sleep?
他们难道光顾着睡觉了吗
Hongjing No. 8 High School is in very poor form.
宏景八中的状态很差
After the goal,
双方进球后
the team members seem to have started blaming each other.
球队的成员好像也开始互相指责
No. 9 Qin Ao and No. 6 Lin Lu miscommunicated.
九号秦敖与六号林鹿配合失误
Yeah,
没错
there's still time!
还有时间
Go for it!
加油
-Captain Fu Xinshu is passing the ball. -Watch the ball!
现在传球的是队长付新书
But the ball has been intercepted!
但是球被抢断了
The ball!
这球
Ning'an shoots!
宁安射门
The ball was saved by Feng Suo!
球被冯锁给扑出
The ball is once again with Hongjing No. 8 High School.
球再次来到了宏景八中的脚下
Number 9, Qin Ao, with his individual skill,
九号秦敖靠着自己的个人能力
has dribbled the ball into the penalty area.
把球带入禁区
Shoot!
射门
Unfortunately, it was also saved by Ning'an's goalkeeper.
可惜同样被宁安的门将扑出
Both sides have exchanged attacks and defenses,
双方攻守互换
neither gaining an absolute advantage.
都没有拿到绝对的优势
The running speed of both teams' players
双方球员的跑动速度
has noticeably slowed down on the field.
在场上明显是慢了下来
Lack of endurance
一直以来
has always been Ning'an's weakness.
耐力不足都是宁安队的短板
However, Hongjing Team has clearly lacked training for 2 years,
但宏景队两年明显疏于训练
and their stamina is also failing to keep up.
体力也有些跟不上了
Why is he still here?
他怎么还在这里
Could it be that he
难道他
also likes watching football matches?
也爱看球
You know about football, too?
你也懂足球啊
A little bit.
懂一点
Watch the game.
看球
Hongjing's No. 10 is advancing at high speed with the ball.
宏景的十号带球高速向前
The 2 players collided for the ball, and the ball was intercepted!
这球两个人发生碰撞被抢断了
They crashed into each other.
撞到了一起
Fu Xinshu was knocked down,
付新书被撞倒
falling heavily to the ground.
狠狠地倒在了地上
The right side!
右边
Ning'an dribbled past Hongjing's No. 5, Yu Ming.
宁安带球过掉了宏景的五号俞明
He's still advancing.
他在继续向前
Hongjing Team's No. 12 used his body to block,
宏景队的十二号用身体拦截
but the referee blew the whistle!
但是裁判响哨
-Looks like No. 12 committed a handball! -Calm down, calm down.
十二号好像是手球了
What's happening?
这怎么了
The referee thinks
现在裁判认为
your defending player
你方后卫队员
opened his arms in the opponent's penalty area,
在对方禁区张开双臂
and his arm touched the ball,
手臂触球
so a penalty kick was awarded.
判了一个点球
So did he actually commit a handball?
那他手球了吗
From my angle,
从我这个角度看
no.
没有
-What? Do that again, and you're off. -Alright, it's okay.
你干嘛 再来出去啊
He even blew the whistle for that.
这样也吹啊
Let's go.
走 走 走
What should we do in this situation?
那现在这种情况该怎么办
This is the first lesson for you—
现在就开始你的第一课
obey the referee's decisions.
服从裁判判罚
The first lesson for me?
我的第一课
So pretentious.
真装
Never mind.
算了
We're just going through the motions anyway.
本来也只是随便走走过场
The referee has finally ruled
裁判最终判定
that Hongjing's No. 12, Chen Weidong, handled the ball
宏景十二号陈卫东手球
and awarded a penalty kick to Ning'an.
判罚给宁安队一个点球
Possession goes back to Ning'an.
球权再次来到宁安队这边
Next is a tense penalty kick.
接下来是紧张刺激的点球
Ning'an Team's No. 14 is
宁安队十四号球员
standing at the penalty mark.
站在十二码线前
It's a test for the goalkeeper, Feng Suo.
考验门将冯锁的时候到了
Run-up, shoot!
助跑 打门
It's in again.
球又进了
Two to zero.
二比零
Ning'an Experimental School extends its lead.
宁安实验扩大了领先的优势
For Hongjing No. 8 High School,
这对宏景八中来说
this is like a blatant slap in the face.
是赤裸裸地打脸
We shouldn't have come here to embarrass ourselves!
就不该来丢这个人
Your safety comes first.
没事就好
Are you trying to discipline us or save us?
是要管教我们还是拯救我们
Sorry,
不好意思
we are just lousy students.
我们就是垃圾学生
Please stay away from us.
麻烦您离我们远点
They may look careless and carefree,
他们看起来吊儿郎当
talking like winning or losing doesn't matter.
嘴上说着无谓输赢
But in fact,
但其实
their faces clearly show their unwillingness to lose,
他们的脸上分明写满了不甘心
their anger,
愤怒
and their helplessness.
无力
Going through the motions?
走过场
It doesn't look like that.
不太像
Do they really not want to win?
他们真的不想赢吗
Lin Lu, are you alright?
林鹿 没事吧
-I'm fine. Let's continue! -Are you okay?
没事 没事 继续
No.
不
These kids who say they don't care
这群说着无所谓的孩子
actually do care.
其实并不是无所谓
They really want to win.
他们真的想赢
They yearn for victory more than anyone else.
他们比任何人都想赢
The fire burning in their eyes,
那眼神里烧着的火
the relentless futile efforts,
那一次次徒劳
yet the refusal to stop running—
却不肯停下的奔跑
none of them can be faked.
骗不了人
Do you want to win?
想赢吗